<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter [
<!ENTITY xmlns "http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
]>

<chapter xmlns="&xmlns;">
  
  <info>
    <title>Day 10</title>
    <subtitle>Adding Bootstrap Elements to the Home Page</subtitle>
  </info>

  <para>
    At this point in the documentation, I will compeletely change the style.  Up to this point, getting set up has been very procedural and comprehensive.  From now on, there is a lot of modification to the source that will NOT be covered.  Instead, the documentation will serve as a sort of log to document the resources used in a step-wise, descriptive way.
  </para>

  <procedure>
    <title>
      Bootstrapping the Project
    </title>

    <para>
      Again, this is in now way meant to be comprehensive.  The doc is now basically a bullet point log of what was accomplished on a given day to serve as a reference.
    </para>

    <step>
      <para>
        Added a "Container" to the app
      </para>
      <para>
        This was done in <sgmltag>./views/layouts/application.html.erb</sgmltag>
      </para>
    </step>

    <step>
      <para>
        Create a header at the "layouts level" by creating the file <sgmltag>_header.html.erb</sgmltag>
      </para>
      <para>
        The underscore is quite important and basically means that this is file is going to get referenced by a "partial"
      </para>
      <para>
        Link to the partial by adding embedded ruby code to the HTML in <sgmltag>./app/views/layouts/application.html.erb</sgmltag>
      </para>
    </step>

    <step>
      <para>
        Go to <ulink>getbootstrap.com/components/#navbar</ulink> to find the code for the navbar (this will be nested in "div" tags).
      </para>
      <para>
        Copy and paste a bunch of the code for the navbar in the header into the partial <sgmltag>_header.html.erb</sgmltag> and be sure to get the "div" tags along with everything inside.
      </para>
    </step>

    <step>
      <para>
        Things will still not fully work because we need to include the Bootstrap's Javascript by modifying the <sgmltag>./app/assets/javascripts/application.js</sgmltag>
      </para>
      <para>
        Add the line of code: <sgmltag>//= require bootstrap-sprockets</sgmltag>
      </para>
    </step>

    <step>
      <para>
        Grab the "viewport" code from <ulink>http://getbootstrap.com/getting-started/#template</ulink>
      </para>
      <para>
        Copy the "meta" tags and everything inside for "viewport"
      </para>
      <para>
        Add a "viewport" for mobile device support at <sgmltag>./views/layouts/application.html.erb</sgmltag>
      </para>
      <para>
        Add the viewport code to the code at the bottom of the head tag (still inside the head tags)
      </para>
    </step>

    <step>
      <para>
        Add a div class="jumbotron" to the top of the home page
      </para>
      <para>
        Go to <ulink>getbootstrap.com/css/#buttons</ulink> to get support for button customization
      </para>
      <para>
        This is done for the sign up button and is done all inside of the embedded ruby in the form of an argument.
      </para>
    </step>

  </procedure>


<!-- add "procedure" -->


<!--

  <procedure>
    <title>

    </title>

    <step>
      <para>

      </para>
    </step>


  </procedure>

-->

</chapter>