<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter [
<!ENTITY xmlns "http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
]>

<chapter xmlns="&xmlns;">
  
  <info>
    <title>Day 6</title>
    <subtitle>Home Page Generation (Setting the Root Path) and "Routing" with Rails</subtitle>
  </info>

  <procedure>
    <title>
      Creating the Home Page with Rails
    </title>
    <step>
      <para>
        Go to the root of the project
      </para>
    </step>

    <step>
      <para>
        Run <sgmltag>$ rails server</sgmltag>
      </para>
      <para>
        This will obviously need to be done whenever we are running the project off of our machine
      </para>
    </step>

    <step>
      <para>
        Received and error when running <sgmltag>$ rails server</sgmltag> from cygwin (I wonder if this is just a cygwin problem)
      </para>
      <para>
        Just tried running <sgmltag>$ bundle install</sgmltag> from cygwin and seeing some new "Installing" messages
      </para>
      <para>
        It is currently held up on <sgmltag>Installing pkg-config 1.1.7</sgmltag>
      </para>
      <para>
        Nevermind - this worked! It just took a really long time.
      </para>
      <para>
        Next time add verbose output with <sgmltag>$ bundle install -V</sgmltag>
      </para>
      <para>
        Attempting to run <sgmltag>$ rails server</sgmltag> again...
      </para>
      <para>
        Success! It worked!
      </para>
      <para>
        Additionally, it looked like it installed a bunch of new packages.  I do not know why these were missed the last time I ran <sgmltag>$ bundle install</sgmltag> the last time with GitBash.
      </para>
    </step>

    <step>
      <para>
        Keep the server running, and in another instance of terminal, create a home page by entering <sgmltag>$ rails generate controller pages home</sgmltag>
      </para>
      <para>
        Observe output like "create", "route", and "invoke"
      </para>
      <para>There should not be any error messages here</para>
    </step>

    <step>
      <para>
        Run <sgmltag>$ git status</sgmltag> to see what has been added to the project
      </para>
    </step>

    <step>
      <para>
        Navigate to the new page at <sgmltag>localhost:3000/pages/home</sgmltag>
      </para>
      <para>Shold be a brand new page there</para>
    </step>

    <step>
      <para>
        From the root of the project folder, go to <sgmltag>./app/views/pages/home.html.erb</sgmltag>
      </para>
      <para>
        With the server still running, make edits to the page (inside of the existing HTML tags)
      </para>
      <para>
        Save the work and refresh the browser and see that the changes live!
      </para>
    </step>

  </procedure>


  <procedure>
    <title>
      Redirecting the Home Page - aka "Routing"
    </title>

    <step>
      <para>
        Routes can be found inside of <sgmltag>./config/routs.rb</sgmltag>
      </para>
      <para>
        Content in that file was created when we ran the generate command for the home page in the last chapter ("day").
      </para>
    </step>

    <step>
      <para>
        Change the first line where <sgmltag>get</sgmltag> appears to <sgmltag>root "pages#home"</sgmltag>
      </para>
    </step>

    <step>
      <para>
        Reload the page where "home" used to be and get a routing error
      </para>
      <para>
        Go to <sgmltag>localhost:3000</sgmltag> (ie. root) and observe the location of the new home page
      </para>
    </step>

    <para>
      The next section will cover "controllers" and "views" and, basically, explain what we did in this section.
    </para>

  </procedure>


<!--

  <procedure>
    <title>

    </title>
    <step>
      <para>

      </para>
    </step>
  </procedure>

-->

</chapter>